<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title> on spcmd </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://spcmd.github.io/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 12:16:53 CET</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>spotymenu: control spotify via dmenu</title>
      <link>http://spcmd.github.io/2016/02/29/spotymenu-control-spotify-via-dmenu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 12:16:53 CET</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spcmd.github.io/2016/02/29/spotymenu-control-spotify-via-dmenu/</guid>
      <description>I while ago it became a pain in the ass for me to select and arrange albums with Spotify&amp;rsquo;s GUI. It&amp;rsquo;s slow, feels heavy and bloated. I wanted something quicker and easier to use, especially something what I can control with the keyboard. I know there is mopidy-spotify and other libspotify based applications too, but those work only with premium accounts. I&amp;rsquo;ve found a bunch of scripts, but those only do basic Spotify controls via dbus (play/pause, prev/next etc.).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run terminal applications from dmenu with their Xresources name</title>
      <link>http://spcmd.github.io/2016/02/24/run-terminal-applications-from-dmenu-with-their-xresources-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 15:20:00 CET</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spcmd.github.io/2016/02/24/run-terminal-applications-from-dmenu-with-their-xresources-name/</guid>
      <description>If you are using dmenu, you might want to run terminal applications from it. I&amp;rsquo;ve found an old post about a modified dmenu_run script in the Arch Linux Forums, in the Dmenu Hacking Thread: #45. It worked fine, but I&amp;rsquo;m using urxvt with .Xresources color definitions for some apps. So I modded that script a bit to use the .Xresources name when it&amp;rsquo;s given. For that to work, you need to create list with the names of the apps in ~/.dmenu_term_apps, for example: $cat ~/.dmenu_term_apps htop alsamixer ranger -name ranger mocp -name moc newsbeuter -name newsbeuter rtorrent -name rTorrent If the -name &amp;lt;name&amp;gt; was given, the app will use its own Xresources settings, otherwise it will use the default settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dmenu2 modding</title>
      <link>http://spcmd.github.io/2016/02/24/dmenu2-modding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 15:00:32 CET</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spcmd.github.io/2016/02/24/dmenu2-modding/</guid>
      <description>About a month ago I started using dmenu (dmenu2, precisely), but I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the behaviour of the TAB key (completion). I wanted it to behave like Vimperator: TAB key to select the next element, Shift+TAB to select the previous. So I modified the dmenu.c file in the source and now it works the way I wanted. If you like this TAB behaviour better, you can get this modified version from my dmenu2 repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>urxvt url-select-plus</title>
      <link>http://spcmd.github.io/2016/02/24/urxvt-url-select-plus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 13:36:01 CET</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spcmd.github.io/2016/02/24/urxvt-url-select-plus/</guid>
      <description>For urxvt there is a nice perl extension called url-select, written by Bert Muennich. It was fine until I needed a few more options, especially an option for opening the selected url in an alternative browser. So I made a slight modification: added an option for it, then added another option for opening the selected url with a media player, which is useful for youtube or some other video links. I renamed this modified script to url-select-plus to avoid naming conflicts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog update</title>
      <link>http://spcmd.github.io/2016/01/21/blog-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 11:19:45 CET</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spcmd.github.io/2016/01/21/blog-update/</guid>
      <description>Long time since I updated this blog, if you read this, it means I&amp;rsquo;ve just successfully migrated from jekyllrb to Hugo. The migration wasn&amp;rsquo;t hard, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t super easy either. I had a few bumps, I had to read the documentation apparently, but so far I like it. I also cleaned up a bit, removed some old, obsolete posts. I hope I can write some new, helpful/useful post in the near future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix: Acer Laptop freezes with Arch Linux and other systemd based distros</title>
      <link>http://spcmd.github.io/2015/05/24/fix-acer-laptop-freezes-with-arch-linux-and-other-systemd-based-distros/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spcmd.github.io/2015/05/24/fix-acer-laptop-freezes-with-arch-linux-and-other-systemd-based-distros/</guid>
      <description>I had a problem with Arch-based (or systemd based?) distros with my Acer ES1-512 laptop. Every time I used systemctl suspend or pm-suspend the whole system just totally froze. Shutdown didn&amp;rsquo;t work either: the system was shut down, but the laptop didn&amp;rsquo;t turn off (screen backlight was on, and the fans were working too). I tried a bunch of kernels, systemd versions, different kernel parameters, but neither of them worked. A week ago I installed Arch again and played around with the BIOS settings (again).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vimpv</title>
      <link>http://spcmd.github.io/2015/04/25/vimpv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spcmd.github.io/2015/04/25/vimpv/</guid>
      <description>Vimpv is a javascript plugin for Vimperator which allows you to follow/open video urls with mpv. Tested on Youtube and Vimeo. Usage: The default key map is ;m You can map the default key to something else, for example, if you don&amp;rsquo;t use the mark command, you can map it to m in your ~/.vimperatorrc: nmap m ;m You can find the plugin in my dotfiles repo: https://github.com/spcmd/dotfiles/blob/master/vimperator/.vimperator/plugin/vimpv.js</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ignotifier-setbadge</title>
      <link>http://spcmd.github.io/2015/04/25/ignotifier-setbadge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spcmd.github.io/2015/04/25/ignotifier-setbadge/</guid>
      <description>Since the Gmail Notifier (ignotifier) addon doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow us to change its icon badge color (and it cannot be styled via css), I made a simple bash script which allows us to change those colors. You can the find the script and the documentation on github: https://github.com/spcmd/ignotifier-setbadge</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://spcmd.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spcmd.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Where you can find me: github gist reddit logout.hu spcmdgit [at] gmail [dot] com (only for important cases please!) System &amp;amp; tools: Arch Linux + Awesome WM Void Linux + Awesome WM Main Browser: Firefox Terminal: URxvt Shell: Zsh Text/Code Editor: Vim File Manager: ranger Mail Client: mutt RSS reader: newsbeuter</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim Easy TODO</title>
      <link>http://spcmd.github.io/2015/04/11/vim-easy-todo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spcmd.github.io/2015/04/11/vim-easy-todo/</guid>
      <description>Today I released my very first Vim plugin called Vim Easy TODO. I&amp;rsquo;m using Vim for about 3 weeks now, and I like it a lot. I still have a lot to learn, but I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to it. I needed some To-do list plugin like PlainTasks for Sublime Text. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to use some &amp;ldquo;heavy&amp;rdquo; plugin, I just needed to have some basic, formatted/colorized To-do list. So I decided to write it for myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>qxbacklight</title>
      <link>http://spcmd.github.io/2015/03/20/qxbacklight/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spcmd.github.io/2015/03/20/qxbacklight/</guid>
      <description>A bash script for setting the brightness with xbacklight quickly. Dependencies xbacklight Installation Clone the repository (https://github.com/spcmd/qxbacklight.git) or download from Github. Copy qxbacklight to somewhere in your $PATH (for example: ~/bin) or copy wherever you like, then give the full path to the script when using it. Make it executable (for example: chmod +x /path/to/qxbacklight) Open the script with a text editor and configure the options (see Configurable Options and the detailed comments in the script).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox &gt; mpv</title>
      <link>http://spcmd.github.io/2015/03/17/firefox--mpv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spcmd.github.io/2015/03/17/firefox--mpv/</guid>
      <description>Simple bash script for opening youtube videos and other videos in mpv from Firefox &amp;amp; log watched videos (into a local html file), if you want. Currently the logging option works only with Youtube and Vimeo videos. Update (2015.04.20.): added auto stop/play Spotify options. You can find the documentation and the instructions on the Github page: https://github.com/spcmd/firefox-mpv</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obsnapper</title>
      <link>http://spcmd.github.io/2015/03/16/obsnapper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spcmd.github.io/2015/03/16/obsnapper/</guid>
      <description>I made this bash script for window snapping function under Openbox. I made this for practicing bash and for my personal use. I don&amp;rsquo;t plan on taking feature requests or whatever. However, It works for me, so I decided to share this as a project. I&amp;rsquo;m using this script under Ubuntu 14.04 with Openbox 3.5.2 and tint2 0.11+svn20121014 at resolution 1366x768 and 1280x800. Features Window snapping to left and right Restoring window position or restoring window to a fixed position Dependencies xwininfo xprop wmctrl using a panel or dock with openbox Configurable options PANEL_NAME=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; (string ; name of the panel or dock ; for example: tint2) PANEL_ID=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; (string ; only if PANEL_NAME is not working ; for example: 0x40006b) PANEL_TYPE=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; (string ; options: left, top, bottom) PX_CORR_LPT= (integer ; some pixel correction, mainly beacause of borders ; you can use this when PANEL_TYPE is set to &amp;ldquo;left&amp;rdquo; ; for example: 2) RESTORE_BEHAVIOUR=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; (string ; options: dynamic, fixed) TOP_MARGIN= (integer ; margin from the top (in pixel), when RESTORE_BEHAVIOUR is set to &amp;ldquo;fixed&amp;rdquo; ; for example: 10) Notes: Do not use quotation marks (&amp;quot;&amp;quot;) with integer type options!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

